Guide to the Institute for Defense and Disarmament Studies Records, 1974-2007.
Institute for Defense and Disarmament Studies Records
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Institute for Defense and Disarmament Studies Records, 1974-2007.
8588
27
Audio recordings, computer media, videos, correspondence, printed materials, newspapers.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Collection includes material relating to the Nuclear Weapons Freeze Campaign (NWFC), reports, correspondence, Democratic National Committee material, Political Action Committee (PAC) material, Randy Forsberg publications and speeches and a print copy of her PhD Thesis, IDDS publications, audio/video material, print copies of the Arms Control Reporter, other administrations files.
The Institute for Defense and Disarmament Studies (IDDS) was a nonprofit center, founded by Dr. Randall Caroline Forsberg, that studied global military policies, arms holdings, production and trade, arms control and peace-building efforts. It also ran educational programs on current and alternative policies.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Collection includes material relating to the Nuclear Weapons Freeze Campaign (NWFC), reports, correspondence, Democratic National Committee material, Political Action Committee (PAC) material, Randy Forsberg publications and speeches and a print copy of her PhD Thesis, IDDS publications, audio/video material, print copies of the Arms Control Reporter, other administrations files.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Forsberg, Randall.; Democratic National Committee (U.S.).; Nuclear Weapons Freeze Campaign.
Titles:
Arms Control Reporter.
Subjects:
Arms control.; Arms race.; Disarmament.; Military; Military policy.; Political action committees.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Reports from International Conferences about Euromissiles, 1982-1983 (Box 1)
- Information about anti-missiles movements in different European countries, 1982-1983 (Box 1)
- Correspondence with the European partner organizations, 1982-1983 (Box 1)
- Euromissiles political delegation project, 1982-1983 (Box 1)
- Europeace Tour 1983, 1982-1983 (Box 1)
- Lobbying, 1982-1983 (Box 1)
- IDDS Contacts/Mailing Lists, Undated (Box 1)
- Calendars, notebooks, address books, 1980-1991, Undated (Box 1)
- Nuclear Weapons Freeze Campaign (NWFC) material, 1981-1986 (Box 2)
- Clippings public polls, Date unknown (Box 2)
- General elections, Democratic party, 1982 (Box 2)
- Freeze Newsletters from Vol.1 no.3 to Vol. 4 no.7, 1981-10-1984-08 (Box 2)
- Randall Forsberg’s US visits and international trips/talks, 1988-1989 (Box 3)
- Variety of IDDS administration materials, 1980's (Box 4)
  Including staff, visitors, marketing, press statements, seminars and correspondence
- State and Local Campaign, Freeze Voter ’84 (FV’84), 1982-1984 (Box 5, Folder 1-17)
- Political, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 18-40)
  National U.S organizations, electoral procedures, Democratic National Committee, Democratic Congressional Campaign, Political Action Committee (PAC)
- Correspondence, 1983-1984 (Box 5, Folder 41-54)
  NWFC correspondence with local organizers, Democratic Candidates for Congress and correspondence regarding Freeze campaign
- National Committee Freeze Campaign, 1983-1984 (Box 5, Folder 55-66)
- National Committee Freeze Campaign, 1983-1984 (Box 6, Folder 1-19)
- Disarmament, 1980-1984 (Box 6, Folder 20-24)
  Disarmament ideas, papers, proposals, clippers, pamphlets, UN disarmament
- Freeze materials, 1980's (Box 7, Folder 1-10)
  Clippings about the Freeze, Reagan on the Freeze, clippings on redbaiting, responses to redbaiting, international freeze climate, 5 continents peace initiative, Soviets proposals and attitudes, International Freeze – Stockholm conference
- Mixed materials: strategies and proposals, 1980's (Box 7, Folder 11-15)
- Randall Forsberg’s trips/conferences, 1982-1987 (Box 7, Folder 16-86)
- Randall Forsberg’s trips/conferences, 1982-1987 (Box 8, Folder 1-12)
- Randall Forsberg’s trips/conferences, 2002 (Box 8, Folder 13)
- Randall Forsberg’s trips/conferences, 2002 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  Contains grouping of folders
- Press materials/clippings about Randy Forsberg and Freeze, 1980-1987 (Box 8, Folder 15)
- Correspondence, newsclippings, President Bush, 1978-1990 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  Contains grouping of folders; includes info-folder about a documentary project “To What End” 1988, folder about Randy Forsberg pre-Malta summit briefing for President George Bush 1989 and IDDS Briefing Paper 1987"
- Arms control, 1981-1988 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  Contains grouping of folders; includes copies of Arms Control Today, Bulletin of the Atomic Scientists, ADIU Report (Armament and Disarmament Information Unit), 2 copies of paper “Defining and Implementing the FREEZE – Outline of Workshop" by Randall Forsberg
- Important speeches, including UN speech, 1979-1982 (Box 8, Folder 18)
- Mixed material, 1978, 1979, 1984 (Box 8, Folder 19)
  Contains grouping of folders: newspapers clippings and articles (nuclear warfare, military budgets, civil defense, missile defense, nuclear proliferation, arms race overview); research about different topics; some speeches by Randy Forsberg
- Freeze materials, 1979-1983 (Box 8, Folder 20)
  Contains grouping of folders; includes original IDDS Brochures 1981 – Freeze and Beyond: Confining the Military Defense as Route to Disarmament - original world policy summary, and papers by Matthew Evangelista, Mark Niedergang, and Forsberg
- Early speeches, lectures, photos, 1979-1988 (Box 8, Folder 21)
- Freeze research, 1980-1984 (Box 8, Folder 22)
  Contains grouping of folders; includes early papers and speeches by Randy Forsberg
- "Verifying a comprehensive freeze", by Karl Pieragostini, 1983 (Box 8, Folder 23)
- Original copies of publications by the IDDS staff, 1981-1984 (Box 8, Folder 24)
- Statement of Randall Forsberg, “USSR is not ahead”, 1982-03-31 (Box 8, Folder 25)
- Mixed material, 1979-1980 (Box 8, Folder 26)
  The Boston Study Group, A Zero-Based Approach to the FY 1980 Military Budget (2 copies), Revised version April 1979 (2 copies), Memorandum for President Jimmy Carter December 1979 (1 copy)
- "Military and Nuclear Policy Alternatives: Analytical Material", 1982 (Box 8, Folder 27)
- "World Military RandD, Control of the Technological Arms Race", 1978-10 (Box 8, Folder 28)
- "Current Manufacturing and Deployment of US Nuclear Weapon Systems", 1979-01 (Box 8, Folder 29)
- Paper, "Nuclear Imperialists", 1979-09 (Box 9, Folder 1)
- Paper, "A Peace Movement-Wide 'No New Nuclear Weapons' Campaign, To STOP the US-Soviet Nuclear Arms Race", Date unknown (Box 9, Folder 2)
- Paper, "Deterrence vs. Disarmament", 1980 (Box 9, Folder 3)
- Paper, "Public Attitudes Towards War and Arms", 1980-12 (Box 9, Folder 4)
- Paper, "The Prospects for Arms Control and Disarmament, a View from Moscow", 1981-12 (Box 9, Folder 5)
- Paper, "Strategy for a Concerted National Effort to Halt the Nuclear Arms Race" (first draft), 1980-08-25 (Box 9, Folder 6)
- The Case for a Nuclear-Weapon Freeze, 1982-03 (Box 9, Folder 7)
- "Testimony at Ad Hoc Hearings on the Full Implications of the Military Budget held by Members of the House Armed Services Committee", 1982-04-01 (Box 9, Folder 8)
- Press Statement of Randall Forsberg at the announcement of the bipartisan, joint House-Senate Freeze Resolution, 1982-03-10 (Box 9, Folder 9)
- Case study, "Freezing the Arms Race: The Genesis of a Mass Movement", 1983 (Box 9, Folder 10)
- Randy Forsberg Working Papers, notes, 1974-1979 (Box 9, Folder 11-17)
- Randall Forsberg’s talks in the US and abroad, 1982-1983 (Box 9, Folder 18-61)
- Randall Forsberg’s talks in the US and abroad, 1982-1983 (Box 10, Folder 1-7)
- IDDS Old Correspondence, 1980-1981 (Box 10, Folder 8-13)
- Financial Reports, 1984 (Box 10, Folder 14-29)
- Fundraising, 1984 (Box 11, Folder 1-10)
- Original publicity materials for Freeze Voter 84, 1984 (Box 11, Folder 11-13)
- Information about Freeze Voter 84’ Board Members, 1984 (Box 11, Folder 14-24)
- Correspondence with National Peace Organizations (NWFC), Date unknown (Box 11, Folder 25-26)
- Local contacts and correspondence, 1982-1984 (Box 11, Folder 27-59)
- Local Freeze Campaigns by State, 1980's (Box 12, Folder 1-46)
- Information about US Congress members, 1984 (Box 12, Folder 46-66)
- Invitations to speak at Harvard, “Avoiding Nuclear War” Faculty Seminar series, 1984 (Box 12, Folder 67)
- Invitation - “New England First Strike/First Use”, Boston, 1984-10 (Box 12, Folder 68)
- Correspondence and invitation to University of North California, 1984-10-08 (Box 12, Folder 69)
- Invitation and correspondence regarding conference about “What steps to enduring peace?”, 1984-08-29 (Box 12, Folder 70)
- The Midwest March and Rally for Peace / Chicago Freeze Rally, 1984-10-15 (Box 12, Folder 71)
  Speakers include Jesse Jackson, Helen Caldicott, Randall Forsberg and Herold Washington
- Meeting with the delegates of Dialogue for Peace: American and Soviet Cultural Exchange, 1984-10-15 (Box 12, Folder 72)
- In response to Republican Senator Shamie, 1984-10-22 (Box 12, Folder 73)
  Joint Statement by Jerome Wiesner (MIT), George Rathjens (MIT) and Randall Forsberg (IDDS) regarding Republican Senator Shamie’s statement that the Soviet Union has a disarming nuclear first strike capability, 22 October 1984 (some materials about the first nuclear strike)
- Statement by Randall Forsberg at Midwest Freeze Rally, Chicago, 1984-10-13 (Box 12, Folder 74)
- Talk, "US Foreign and Military Policy 1985-89: Reagan v. Mondale", 1984-11-01 (Box 12, Folder 75)
- Meeting in California, 1984-11-20 (Box 12, Folder 76)
- Australia, 1984-11-20 (Box 12, Folder 77)
  UNGA 39: First Committee / Australian Explanation of Vote on the “FREEZE” resolutions, delivered by Ambassador Richard Butler
- Brooklyn Superintendents’ Symposium on “Living in a Nuclear Age", 1984-11-28 (Box 12, Folder 78)
  Randall Forsberg discusses what would be an appropriate role for schools in educating children for the nuclear age
- WGBH meeting with Alan F. Kay, 1984-12-19 (Box 12, Folder 79)
- WGBH, Zvi Dor-Ner, “The Nuclear Age”, 1984-12-05 (Box 12, Folder 80)
- Keynote speaker invitation, fifth National Freeze Conference in St. Louis, 1984-12 (Box 12, Folder 81)
- Sunday Dinners on Goals and Strategies for Peace, Arms Control and Disarmament, 1985-12 (Box 12, Folder 82)
- Past 1985 Engagements, 1985 (Box 12, Folder 83)
- Funders Conference on Central America, UN Plaza, NYC, 1985-03 (Box 12, Folder 84)
- Third Annual John and Elizabeth Baker Peace Studies Conference on Resolving Soviet-American Differences: How the Cold War Might End, Ohio University, 1986-04 (Box 12, Folder 85)
- FAS and BAS symposium, 1985-01-02 (Box 12, Folder 86)
- Testimony of Randall Forsberg, 1985-07-16 (Box 12, Folder 87)
  Methodist Bishops’ Commission on the Nuclear Crisis and the Pursuit of Peace
- "The Freeze and Beyond", Conference on the Future of Arms Control, 1985-08 (Box 12, Folder 88)
- Greater Cleveland Nuclear Weapons Freeze Campaign, 1985-11-23 (Box 12, Folder 89)
- Talk, Harvard, 1985-04-10 (Box 12, Folder 90)
- IGCC Summer Seminar on Global Security and Arms Control, University of California, 1983-06-23-1983-07-03 (Box 12, Folder 91)
- Alternative Security Conference, Joyce Mertz-Gilmore, 1985-09 (Box 12, Folder 92)
- "From Hiroshima to Star Wars: The challenge of U.S. First Strike Policy, A New England Conference on New Directions for Peace Movement", 1985-10 (Box 12, Folder 93)
- “Forty Years after Hiroshima: Lessons for the Future”, UCAM Educational Association, 1985-11-14 (Box 12, Folder 94)
- Talk on reducing risk of conventional war, 1985-12-04 (Box 12, Folder 95)
  PAWSS Special Seminar Series, New Approaches to Peace and World Security
- Cross-Group Seminar: "Is our national defense consistent with global survival?", 1985-12-12-1985-12-14 (Box 12, Folder 96)
- Conference: "Is Nuclear Disarmament Possible? Or Desirable?", 1987-04-11 (Box 12, Folder 97)
- Third Sarnia Symposium, 1987-03-18-1987-03-21 (Box 12, Folder 98)
- Letter to Randy regarding meeting with students in Utah, 1987-02-25 (Box 12, Folder 99)
- Invitation - keynote speaker at California Conference of the University of California Institute on Global Conflict and Cooperation, 1987-03-26-1987-03-28 (Box 12, Folder 100)
- Talk, Program Corporation of America, Brigham Young University, 1987-03-06 (Box 12, Folder 101)
- Invitation from Joseph S. Nye, 1987-02-20 (Box 12, Folder 102)
  Jr. Director of the Center for Science and International Affairs, Harvard University - meeting regarding preparation of a report for the Ford Foundation about independent institutions in the field of international peace, security, defense and arms control
- Conference: the Past and Future of International Security Studies, Kennedy School of Governance, 1987-02-20 (Box 12, Folder 103)
  Center for Science and International Affairs, Harvard University
- IPIS conference, 1987-01-30-1987-02-01 (Box 12, Folder 104)
- Invitation from the Cornell November 11 Committee to speak at 1986 convocation, 1984-07 (Box 12, Folder 105)
  Press reviews of the convocation and correspondence between Lisbeth Gronland and Randy Forsberg including the report regarding the Boycott of Star Wars Research Founds by University Scientists and Engineers
- Presbyterian Church Consultation on Arms Race, 1986-11-08-1986-11-11 (Box 12, Folder 106)
  Held at Stony Point Center
- Luther College, OIKOS Conference: Building Global Community, 1986-11-05-1986-11-06 (Box 12, Folder 107)
- Invitation to lead an opening discussion and present paper on “Non-Provocative Defense”, 1986-10-15 (Box 12, Folder 108)
- Symposium on averting nuclear war, 1986-09-26-1986-09-28 (Box 12, Folder 109)
- MIT, 1986-09-26-1986-09-27 (Box 12, Folder 110)
- Talk, "Lifting the Shadow of Nuclear War", 1986-09-24 (Box 12, Folder 111)
  Cambridge Forum
- Randy Forsberg on ABC TV, 1987-09-22 (Box 12, Folder 112)
- Symposium, "Beyond deterrence: Avoiding Nuclear War", 1986-09-06 (Box 12, Folder 113)
  The Harvard - Weinberger-Forsberg Panel, an examination of the use of nuclear weapons, and what practical steps the US can take to avoid nuclear war, held at Harvard Kennedy School of Government
- Bradford University, consultation on non-nuclear alternative in Europe, 1986-07-15-1986-07-18 (Box 12, Folder 114)
- Talk, “No First Use of Nuclear Weapons”, 1986-06-20 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  Lawyers Alliance for Nuclear Arms Control, Inc.
- The Northfield Institute for a Global Future, 1986-06-16-1986-06-21 (Box 13, Folder 2)
- Meeting with Michael Randle, 1986-06-09 (Box 13, Folder 3)
- Project on Avoiding Nuclear War, 1987-05-11-1987-05-12 (Box 13, Folder 4)
- NGO Committee on Disarmament (at the UN headquarters), 1987-05-08 (Box 13, Folder 5)
- Harvard ANW, 1986-04-07 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  Outline of report on learning from experience with arms control
- Talk, “Nuclear Weapons: Only a Symptom”, 1986-07-01 (Box 13, Folder 7)
- Invitation to testify on New Zealand’s defense policy, 1986-04 (Box 13, Folder 8)
- Wisconsin Institute for the study of War, Peace and Global Cooperation, Conference, 1986-04-19 (Box 13, Folder 9)
- Ohio University, Department of History, 1986-04-22 (Box 13, Folder 10)
- Program Corporation of America, University of North Carolina, 1986-02-04 (Box 13, Folder 11)
- 25th Anniversary Tribute to Peter, Paul and Mary, 1986-02-25 (Box 13, Folder 12)
  The Free South Africa Movement
- Earlham College, 1986-01-21 (Box 13, Folder 13)
- Women’s Defense Dialogue with NATO, 1987-05-31 (Box 13, Folder 14)
- American Friends Service Committee talks, 1986-04-18-1986-04-19 (Box 13, Folder 15)
- The Nation’s 120th Anniversary Celebration, 1986-03-18 (Box 13, Folder 16)
- The Disarmament 2000: A Working Conference, 1986-06-20-1986-06-21 (Box 13, Folder 17)
- The National Mobilization for Justice and Peace in Central America and Southern Africa, 1986-04-25 (Box 13, Folder 18)
- IDDS correspondence, 1986-1991 (Box 13, Folder 19-28)
- IDDS correspondence, 1990-1993 (Box 14, Folder 1-11)
- IDDS correspondence, 1981-1982 (Box 14, Folder 12-15)
- IDDS correspondence, 1983-1985 (Box 15, Folder 1-12)
- IDDS correspondence, 1985-1988 (Box 16, Folder 1-4)
- Randy Forsberg’s trips, 1988 (Box 16, Folder 5-15)
- Materials related to Freeze Legislation, 1982-1985 (Box 16, Folder 16-25)
- Freeze Voter’84 campaign materials, 1984 (Box 16, Folder 26-41)
- Freeze Voter’84 campaign materials, 1984 (Box 17, Folder 1-6)
- FV’84 strategy, 1984 (Box 17, Folder 7-13)
- Correspondence, reports of trips, conferences, talks and other materials from Randall Forsberg’s years at SIPRI, 1968-1974 (Box 17, Folder 14-21)
- Forsberg’s 1997 PhD Thesis, 1997 (Box 17, Folder 22)
- Arms Control Marketing and Subscriptions, 1970's-2000's (Box 17, Folder 23-30)
- Various audio and video materials, 1980-2000 (Box 18)
  Includes some electronic copies of the Arms Control Reporter for 1990-2003
- Video materials, 1980-2000 (Box 19)
- Correspondence between Randy Forsberg (the IDDS) and the World Policy Institute regarding preparation of the Address to the Next President, 1988 (Box 20, Folder 1)
  Includes copy of “Report to the Next Administration: Outline of the Main Arguments", plus copy of article by Stephen F. Cohen “Will We End the Cold War? The Next President’s Historic Opportunity"
- Correspondence regarding internship positions, 1982-1983 (Box 20, Folder 2)
- Correspondence related to Gender Gap Action Campaign, 1984 (Box 20, Folder 3)
- Correspondence regarding Randy’s review of Josh Goldstein’s book “Long Cycles”, 1988 (Box 20, Folder 4)
- Correspondence regarding TV series “Critical Condition”, 1988-09-21 (Box 20, Folder 5)
- Halt Trident II Missile Petition, 1984-10 (Box 20, Folder 6)
- Randy Forsberg’s endorsement of Harvest of Peace Resolution, 1990-01 (Box 20, Folder 7)
- Helsinki Watch, Union of Concerned Scientists letter of support for the USSR peace and disarmaments movements, 1982-1983 (Box 20, Folder 8)
- Letter from Daniel Ellsberg to Randy Forsberg regarding Independent Voices, 1985-12 (Box 20, Folder 9)
- Correspondence with INFACT (Infant Formula Action Coalition), 1984 (Box 20, Folder 10)
- Correspondence with International Alliance of Atomic Veterans, 1984 (Box 20, Folder 11)
- Funding Proposal to create an Institute for Global Security Studies in Seattle, Pacific Celebration, 1989 (Box 20, Folder 12)
- International Expert Statement on German Unification, 1990-06 (Box 20, Folder 13)
- Program of IPIS conference, 1987-01-30-1987-02-01 (Box 20, Folder 14)
- Correspondence with Jobs with Peace Campaign regarding invitation for Randy Forsberg to become a member of the Advisory Board, 1984-12 (Box 20, Folder 15)
- Correspondence with “John Kerry for Senate”, 1984-11 (Box 20, Folder 16)
- Correspondence with the MacArthur Foundation regarding Randy’s Letter of Reference for Charles Meconis research proposal, 1989-02 (Box 20, Folder 17)
- Letter of protest - major crackdown on Moscow Independent “Peace Group to Establish Trust, 1986 (Box 20, Folder 18)
- Correspondence with National Gray Panther Committee, 1984 (Box 20, Folder 19)
- The National Mobilization for Justice and Peace in Central America and Southern Africa, 1987 (Box 20, Folder 20)
- National Referendum Ecuador, Central America, Undated (Box 20, Folder 21)
- Mobilization for Survival request for Randy’s endorsement of the Nuclear Free Cambridge Campaign, 1983-10 (Box 20, Folder 22)
- Open Letter to American People, 1980 (Box 20, Folder 23)
- Judy Pratt for Senate, 1984 (Box 20, Folder 24)
- Pro Peace the Great Peace March, 1985-11-20 (Box 20, Folder 25)
- The West German scientists’ initiative “Responsibility for Peace”, 1989-01 (Box 20, Folder 26)
- Safe Life on Earth, 1984-05 (Box 20, Folder 27)
- A Benefit for Science for the People, 1984 (Box 20, Folder 28)
- Proposal for the establishment of a Select Committee on Arms Control, 1984-11 (Box 20, Folder 29)
- Randy’s endorsement for the book “Understanding Nuclear Weapons and Arms Control”, 1983-07 (Box 20, Folder 30)
- Third UN Special Session on Disarmament (UN SSD III), 1988-05-1988-06 (Box 20, Folder 31)
- Correspondence regarding Randy’s quote for the book “Beyond the Hotline”, Undated (Box 20, Folder 32)
- War and Peace Foundation, Petitions, 1991 (Box 20, Folder 33)
- Randy’s endorsement for the WILPF proposal to the UN Women’s conference in Nairobi, 1984-1985 (Box 20, Folder 34)
- Support of World Association for World Federation for Actions supporting Non-Aligned Movement’s Declaration and Meeting at the Hague on Strengthening International Law, 1989-06 (Box 20, Folder 35)
- Peace Forum of the Swedish Labor Movement, 1982-04-19 (Box 20, Folder 36)
- Press Conference, Randy’s Statement, 1982-03-29 (Box 20, Folder 37)
- Correspondence with Mary White from the Adult Education Committee, 1982-03-13 (Box 20, Folder 38)
- Correspondence regarding Randy’s talk at the North Shore Town Meeting on Nuclear War, Chicago, 1982-03-21 (Box 20, Folder 39)
- Guns or Butter II – a call for Human Survival, Conference in Youngstown, 1982-03-20 (Box 20, Folder 40)
- Senator Edward Kennedy statements, 1982 (Box 20, Folder 41)
  Includes Randall Forsberg’s Press Statement at the announcement of the Bipartisan, Joint House-Senate Freeze Resolution, March 10, 1982
- Correspondence with Bob Moore, coordinator of the Coalition for Nuclear Disarmament at Princeton, 1982 (Box 20, Folder 42)
- Correspondence regarding a Proposal for an Educational Symposium on “Implementing the Freeze: A New Agenda for Arms Control”, 1984-03-07 (Box 20, Folder 43)
- Statement of Randall Forsberg, IDDS at the National Nuclear Weapons Freeze Campaign Conference, 1982-04-26 (Box 20, Folder 44)
- “Halting and Reversing the Nuclear Arms Race, A challenge to us all”, Northeastern University, 1982-04-24 (Box 20, Folder 45)
- Ohio Nuclear Weapons Freeze, 1982 (Box 20, Folder 46)
  Includes information about June 12 peace demonstration
- Letter from the Seattle Religious Peace Action Coalition (SERPAC/CALC), 1982-04-30 (Box 20, Folder 47)
- Letter from Joan Baez “Humanitas International”, 1982-06-11 (Box 20, Folder 48)
- June 12 March and Rally, Undated (Box 20, Folder 49)
- Plowshare Coffee House and Discussion Center, 1982 (Box 20, Folder 50)
- List of the Non-Governmental Organizations and Peace and Disarmament Institutions, Undated (Box 20, Folder 51)
- MacNeil-Lehrer, 1982-06-17 (Box 20, Folder 52)
  Includes transcribed text of Reagan’s UN address before a Special Session of the UN GA on Disarmament
- 1982 KICKOFF, 1982 (Box 20, Folder 53)
- Materials related to Bush Benefit, Washington D.C., 1989-11-20 (Box 20, Folder 54)
- Press Release Statement by Randall Forsberg on briefing with President Bush, 1989-11-20 (Box 20, Folder 55)
- Jobs with Peace Campaign, The Conference: “The Urban Economy: Victim of Military Spending", 1981-10-03 (Box 20, Folder 56)
- Correspondence regarding Randall Forsberg talk at the Columbia University, 1981-09-30 (Box 20, Folder 57)
- Correspondence regarding Randall Forsberg appearance at the Convention of the United Electrical, Radio and Machine Workers of America, 1981-09-16 (Box 20, Folder 58)
- Freeze Banquet commemorating the bomb of Nagasaki, 1981-08-09 (Box 20, Folder 59)
- Pax Christi, A memorial mass for victims of the Hiroshima-Nagasaki bombings, 1981-08-09 (Box 20, Folder 60)
- Geneva NGOs Urgent Action Conference, 1981-08-05-1981-08-06 (Box 20, Folder 61)
- Logo of the IDDS, Undated (Box 20, Folder 62)
- “The Prospects for Arms Control and Disarmament”, A view from Moscow, “Soviet Report” by Randall Forsberg, 1981-12 (Box 20, Folder 63)
- “The Future of Nuclear Arms Race” by Randall Forsberg - draft and final version, 1981 (Box 20, Folder 64)
- “A Functional Theory of Disarmament” by Randall Forsberg - draft, 1983-07-13 (Box 20, Folder 65)